Finding Aid for the Herschel Burke Gilbert Papers PASC-M.0268
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Rights and Royalties, Series 8.
  - Ballad of the Big Bankroll (Box 289)
    Letter from Dee Katcher to Gilbert and assignment of lyric rights to Ione Reid Lowrance.
  - Chappell & Co. Ltd, correspondence re royalties & royalty statements 1960s (Box 241)
  - Chappell (later Warner Chappell) royalty statements for John Paul Music (Box 250)
  - Copyright registration certificate for the "Big Bankroll", 1962 (Box 267)
  - Copyright registration certificate for "Lonely Man" and "The Fox", 1967 (Box 268)
    Also includes correspondence
  - Correspondence (Box 252)
    between Gilbey Music and Del-Fi Records re: payments for "Something Special" sung by Johnny Crawford
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 252)
    between John Paul Music and Harry Fox
  - Correspondence, 1973 December 31 (Box 252)
    Dec. 31, 1973 letter and draft from HB Gilbert to Rolf Budde re: change from Chappell to Rolf Budde Musikverlage German rights/royalties representation
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 252)
    Correspondence between HB Gilbert and Rolf Budde regarding rights/royalties representation
  - Correspondence (Box 253)
    re: Art Tatum albums
  - Correspondence between Herschel Burke Gilbert and ASCAP re: rights, 1961 list of Picture Titles and Television Series (Box 250)
  - Correspondence between Herschel Burke Gilbert & Chappell & Co. Ltd. (Box 250)
  - Correspondence re: A Kiss But No Petting, 1958 (Box 261)
  - Correspondence re: Gigantis, The Fire Monster Cues, 1964 (Box 261)
  - Correspondence re: John Paul Music and Marlen Music (and Gordon Music) including Witness to Murder score, 1969-1983 (Box 251)
  - Correspondence with Mario Gili re Italy royalties etc 1960s (Box 248)
  - Correspondence, Edward Kassner Music re: Canadian royalties, 1966 (Box 241)
  - Correspondence, Edward Kassner re: England royalties, 1966 (Box 241)
  - Correspondence/agreement with Kassner re Italy royalties, 1958-1966 (Box 241)
  - Corrrespondence re: Lloyd Bridges Show Cues, 1963 (Box 261)
    Letter re: "Lloyd Bridges Show Cues" 1963 (re: resigned members cues: e.g. Alfred Perry + Joseph Mullendore)
  - Cue Sheet Credits, 1966 (Box 261)
    1966 letter Re: correct publisher cue sheet credit for John Paul Music (thru 1960) vs. Gilbey Music (beginning 1961)
  - Distribution Formula: Background Music, 1967 (Box 261)
  - General Music Corporation, correspondence, cue sheets, royalty statements, 1966-1967 (Box 241)
  - German distribution of fees, 1967 (Box 261)
  - Gilbert and John Paul Music Royalty Statements, 1960-1995 (Box 262)
  - Gilbey Music Company, 1967 (Box 268)
    12 songs music and lyric by Steve Roth, and original scores
  - Gilbey Music Company, certificate of registration of claim to copyright for "Something Special", 1962 (Box 268)
    includes correspondence and agreements
  - HBG correspondence with United Artists Corp (& Mr. Sidney Shemel, attorney) re: rights to scores of Bailout at 43,000, The Big Caper, The Monster That Challenged the World, The Vampire (Box 248)
  - IMUA Music Company, Maile Records, 1972 December 13 (Box 272)
    Artists royalties for "Hello Hawaii 12/13/72
  - IMUA Music Company, Maile Records, 1972 December 13 (Box 272)
    Artists royalties for Hello Hawaii
  - Information to Cecil F. Read re: Atkinson Case Superior Court, motion pictures from 1942 which have employed Herschel Burke Gilbert, 1970 May 15 (Box 251)
  - John Paul Music, 1957 (Box 261)
    Motion Picture Music owned, controlled, acquired by John Paul Music
  - John Paul Music Corp Statement of Royalties blank form (Box 250)
  - John Paul Music Corp., 1965-1966 (Box 260)
    Television and film title lists containing music owned or controlled by John Paul Music Corp. (masters)
  - Legal bills from Herbert S. Nusbaum for legal services re: There's a Girl in My Heart, The Bandit, and Barker's Luck (Box 241)
  - Letter from Gilbert to BMI (Box 281)
    re: payments including none for The Rifleman
  - Letter from HB Gilbert to David Chudnow, Mutel Music Library regarding John Paul Music Corp music cues, 1956 December 31 (Box 251)
  - Letter from MGM re: California withholding, 1999 May 31 (Box 251)
  - Marlen Music Company (Box 269)
    rights except US 1954 "Sabre Jet", "Riot in Cell Block Eleven" and "Witness to Murder"
  - Marlen Music Company, 1958 (Box 271)
    reassignment of scores to H. B. Gilbert to the John Paul Music Corporations, subsidiary of RKO Teleradio Pictures.
  - Marlen Music Company 1958 (Box 271)
    correspondence, financial statements related to music composed by H. B. Gilbert and being used by Marlen Music and licensed to TV shows without permission
  - Marlen Music Company statements for royalties, 1957-1961 (Box 269)
  - Memo from Harry Fox Agency to All Licensees, 1984 April 28 (Box 251)
  - Notes and hotel bill - Chappell Transatlantic, EMI, etc., 1973 (Box 253)
  - Phonograph Record Manufacturers' Special Payments Fund, Music Performance Trust Funds and correspondence, 1974-1992 (Box 268)
  - Publisher Distributions, 1961 (Box 261)
  - Publisher Distributions, 1960 (Box 261)
  - Publisher Performance Records, 1957-1960 (Box 262)
  - Publishing Distribution memo, 1957 (Box 261)
  - Royalty earnings statement, John Paul Music Corp from Dot Records (Box 250)
  - Royalty statements (personal) including Famous Music Corp, ABC Records, United Artists, Dot, Decca, Coral Records 1950s-70s (Box 250)
  - Saints and Sinners Cues, 1963 (Box 261)
    Correspondence about rights and royalties.
  - Statement of remittance, royalty statement from Coral Records, 1957 February (Box 251)
  - Television and film title lists, 1958 October 1 (Box 267)
    containing music owned or controlled by John Paul Music Corp. second edition
  - Television and film title lists, 1965-1966 (Box 267)
    containing music owned or controlled by John Paul Music Corp. (masters)
  - Television picture titles and television series titles using music owned by John Paul Music Corp., 1958 April 1 (Box 267)
    1st edition catalog
  - TV Performance Payment Schedule, 1966 (Box 261)
  - Typed and pencil list of Music Performed on TV, Gilbert & Mullendore (Box 253)
  - USA vs ASCAP (Box 261)
    Civil action information.
  - Value of Publisher Performance Points, 1954-1957 (Box 261)
- Recording Logs and Catalogs, Series 9.
  - ASCAP writer performance record, 1956-1960 (Box 268)
    Joseph Mullendore, television and radio
  - Catalogs (Box 284)
    - Cues 14,000 through 15,000; Mutel Music Library, includes humorous & comedy
  - Fourteen Thousand (Box 284)
    original takes
  - Hand written notations of suggested order of a record album (Box 253)
  - Handwritten sheet, John Paul Song Catalog (Box 253)
  - John Paul Music (Box 251)
    Songs & Music owned and published by John Paul Music - list
  - John Paul Music "Eight Thousand" catalog (Box 252)
  - John Paul Music "Fourteen Thousand" Catalog (Box 252)
  - John Paul Music "One Hundred" Catalog (Box 252)
  - John Paul Music "RX" & "X" Bridges & Partials (Box 252)
  - John Paul Music Catalogs (Box 252)
    Cues 1 thru 90 including titles, composers & composers pseudonyms
  - John Paul Music Dance Music in 14 Thousand Catalog (Box 252)
  - John Paul Music Humorous-Comedy Catalog of the Fourteen Thousands (Box 252)
  - John Paul Music Library (Box 251)
    - Background Music Cues composed & recorded especially for Television & Motion Pictures Catalogues: Fourteen Thousand Series, Humorous & Comedy Music Cues, Eight Thousand Music Series, One Hundred Series
  - John Paul Music Timing Sheets (Box 251)
  - Logs and written record of tapes recorded by HB Gilbert, 1956 May 23-25 (Box 250)
    Recorded at Nichols Canyon including Chart for Montages and Superimposurs for Beyond a Reasonable Doubt sung by Bobby Grabeau Friday, May 25, 1956 and by Tony Perkins May 23, 1956
  - Mr. Gilbert's Catalogue - John Paul Music (Box 251)
  - Music recording log, 1966 (Box 268)
    and correspondence regarding Nick Stoddard songs
  - Notebook with Music Catalogs (Box 252)
    The Rifleman, Robert Taylor's Detectives, Fourteen Thousand-John Paul Music
  - Picture Titles and Television Series Titles Using Music Owned by John Paul Music Corp., 1961 December (Box 251)
  - Screen Credits, 1957-1958 (Box 261)
    (for Composing, Conducting, Music Directing): Herschel B. Gilbert
  - Song submission sheets, 1959 (Box 253)
  - Television Film Titles containing music owned or controlled by John Paul Music (ASCAP), Gilbey Music (BMI) (Box 251)
  - Television Film Titles containing music owned or controlled by John Paul Music, Third Edition, 1965 June 30 (Box 252)
  - Television Picture Titles & Television Series Titles using music owned by John Paul Music, 1961 October 1 (Box 251)
    catalog
  - Television Picture Titles & Television Series Titles using music owned by John Paul Music, 1958 October 1 (Box 251)
  - Trudy's Records (Gertrude Gilbert) (Box 278)
    - Rifleman & Detectives, Hans Salter Catalog, John Paul Licenses from 4 Star, lists of outgoing mail, both business and personal
  - Various Recordings, 1966-1970 (Box 265)
- Performing Rights Societies, Series 10.
  - ASCAP, 2000 (Box 243)
    American Society of Composers, Authors & Publishers (ASCAP) legal response to protest by Richard Lewis Warren, 2000
  - ASCAP, 1968 (Box 246)
    Chronology of Dolan Proceedings vs. ASCAP, legal documents
  - ASCAP (Box 249)
    proposed amendments to Articles of Association by Oscar Hammerstein II
  - ASCAP (Box 249)
    ASCAP ballots for proposed amendments to Articles of Association by Oscar Hammerstein II
  - ASCAP, 1972 January (Box 249)
    ASCAP Today booklet
  - ASCAP (Box 249)
    Correspondence between Herschel Burke Gilbert & ASCAP re change from John Paul Music Corp to dba
  - ASCAP (Box 249)
    ASCAP Official First Day Cover, W.C. Handy, Father of the Blues 6-cent stamp
  - ASCAP (Box 249)
    ASCAP Consent Order - letter and pamphlet
  - ASCAP, 1950-1969 (Box 249)
    Correspondence between Herschel Burke Gilbert & ASCAP 1950s and 1960s
  - ASCAP, 1960 October 28 (Box 249)
    ASCAP schedule of awards, Panel for Popular Awards.
  - ASCAP, 1961 February 10 (Box 249)
    ASCAP correspondence re: Withholding of credits - modification of regulation.
  - ASCAP, 1976 (Box 250)
    Extension of Herschel Burke Gilbert membership in ASCAP, 1976 through 1985, 1986-1995
  - ASCAP, 1967 (Box 250)
    List of ASCAP licensed television stations.
  - ASCAP, 1959-1977 (Box 250)
    Financial reports
  - ASCAP, 1968-1969 (Box 251)
    ASCAP correspondence re: assignment rights, John Paul Music
  - ASCAP, 1928 (Box 251)
    ASCAP correspondence re: Dutch control of catalog, John Paul Music
  - ASCAP, 1969 June (Box 252)
  - ASCAP, 1967 (Box 252)
    ASCAP Today booklet, autumn, 1967
  - ASCAP, 1959 (Box 261)
    ASCAP letter to membership with reprint of Walter Winchell column 1959 re: protection for musical works
  - ASCAP, 1959 (Box 261)
    ASCAP letter to membership re: Victor Herbert 100th anniversary celebration + Herbert Eulogy in Congressional Record 1959
  - ASCAP, 1964 (Box 261)
    Mexico Registration of works
  - ASCAP, 1959 (Box 261)
    correspondence re: whether 2 L.A. Restaurants were licensed
  - ASCAP, 1959 (Box 261)
    correspondence re: correct Listing for John Paul Music
  - ASCAP, 1958 (Box 261)
    Correspondence to ASCAP from Herschel Gilbert re: Edward Ocnoff membership application
  - ASCAP, 1977 August (Box 261)
    brochure
  - ASCAP, 1977-1978 (Box 261)
    Statement of Receipts and Expenses
  - ASCAP, 1979 (Box 261)
  - ASCAP, 1971 (Box 261)
  - ASCAP, 1970 (Box 261)
    meeting notice
  - ASCAP, 1968 (Box 261)
    Proposed amendment #9876
  - ASCAP, 1960 (Box 261)
    Doc. #7583 new developments
  - ASCAP, 1958 June (Box 261)
    General membership meeting
  - ASCAP, 1959-1961 (Box 261)
    Newsletter
  - ASCAP, 1958,1961 (Box 269)
    television extension agreement
  - ASCAP, 1952-1976 (Box 269)
    resignation, and information regarding remaining music in the ASCAP catalog 1952-1976, HBG ASCAP card 1958
  - ASCAP, 1958 (Box 269)
    Natalie P. Kissel, Program Department, correspondence
  - ASCAP, 1960 (Box 269)
    Gilbert resignation
  - ASCAP, 1963-1976 (Box 269)
    membership applications, various composers
  - ASCAP, 1952-1969 (Box 269)
    correspondence, forms, and brochures
  - ASCAP, 2001-2002 (Box 270)
    ASCAP answer to the fourth Protest of member Richard Lewis Warren, 2001-2002, Gilbert served on an ASCAP committee associated with the response
  - BMI, 1965-1984 (Box 267)
    TV theme and background royalty statement, Foreign royalties statement, US Feature Royalties statement
  - BMI, 1967-1976 (Box 270)
    contracts/agreements
  - BMI, 1975 July 1 (Box 270)
    payment schedule effective July 1, 1975
  - BMI, 1963-1974 (Box 270)
    correspondence
  - BMI, 1960 (Box 270)
    BMI brochure titles "Twenty Years of Service to Music" printed in New York in 1960
  - BMI - ASCAP, 1960 (Box 269)
    membership transference
  - CBS, BMI, ASCAP, 1966-1967 (Box 245)
    Legal: CBS, BMI, ASCAP, 1969, Fortnightly Corp v. United Artists TV, 1967, Frontiere and Markowitz v. Marcus, Stein, Zissu, 1966
  - John Paul Music Corp., 1957 (Box 251)
    RKO Music cover letter and ASCAP election to membership, John Paul Music Corp
  - List by country, 1972 (Box 267)
  - Titles Using Music Owned by John Paul Music Corp. (Box 250)
- Four Star, Series 11.
  - Accounting Correspondence (Box 281)
    Four Star TV - Accounting to Gilbert
  - Album cover, Gene Barry, star of "Burke's Law" Sings of Love and Things (Box 299)
  - Annual Report, 1963 June 29 (Box 281)
  - Annual Reports, 1970, 1971, 1973 (Box 281)
  - Billings re: music, 1959-1964 (Box 281)
  - Binder of cue and log sheets, 1964 (Box 290)
    for various productions
  - Binder of music cues, 1961-1962 (Box 290)
    Titles and composers.
  - Comments regarding HB Gilbert contract with BNP Publishing, documents re: Laurel Music Enterprises and Four Star (Box 281)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 252)
    May & July, 1959, letters from Campbell Connelly & Co. Music Publishers to Gilbert re: British representation.
  - Correspondence (Box 281)
    re: filing an opposition to a patent for The Rifleman telescopic sight for rifles
  - Correspondence (Box 281)
    re: Gilbert contract negotiation and legal matters between Four Star and him
  - Correspondence, 1961 August 22 (Box 281)
    Re: Johnny Crawford's new record
  - Costs of Mexico recordings through Laurel Music (Box 281)
  - Cue Sheets (Box 251)
  - Cue Sheets, 1962-1963 (Box 267)
  - Cue Sheets, Licenses, Transfer Records (including 1964 Burke's Law), correspondence (Box 250)
  - Four Star Bills Paid (re: music) (Box 282)
  - Four Star Christmas Special, open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 149)
    Tape Reel: 728.
  - Four Star Music Dept., open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 185)
    Tape Reel: 325. Log or Cue# N-1512X1S - N-1518X1S.
  - Four Star Television Presents "Wall Street Speaks to Chet Huntley": record album, mock-ups and finished product (Box 299)
  - Herschel Burke Gilbert - Four Star profit participation records (Box 283)
  - Laurel Music Enterprises, Inc. Contracts, 1959 (Box 281)
    Between Gilbert and Four Star Sussex.
  - Laurel-Four Star billings, 1960-1964 (Box 281)
  - Letter to BMI, 1963 (Box 281)
    re: People Will Talk music cue sheets - pre-empted show
  - Letter to Four Star Television stockholders from Dick Powell, 1962 October (Box 247)
  - Music cue sheets (Box 282)
  - Mutel Music Cue Sheets (Box 282)
  - Notebook of Music Catalogs (Box 283)
    The Rifleman, Robert Taylor's Detectives, Fourteen Thousand (John Paul Music)
  - Outline of annual shareholders' meeting (Box 281)
    to be held October 15, 1963
  - Pages of ASCAP and BMI Agreements (Box 255)
  - Press Release (Box 281)
    "Lend an Ear!!! Music and 'The Dick Powell Show'" re: Gilbert and his role
  - Recording Logs (Box 298)
    Music Recording logs for The Dick Powell Show, The Rifleman, The Lloyd Bridges Show, McKeever and the Colonel, Ensign O'Toole,
  - Sound Recording, 1962 July 2; open reel audio tape, 1/2 in. (Box 194)
    Tape Reel: 1092.
  - Sound Recordings, open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 185)
    Tape Reels: 323 and 329. Log or Cue# 14067 and 15367-15389.
  - Staff Sheet lists (Box 284)
  - Statement of Income & Expense, 1963 September 29 (Box 251)
    B.N.P. Publishing Co. Financial Statements
  - Thank you note from Shirley, HB Gilbert's secretary/assistant Four Star annual shareholder reports and stock option plan plus HB Gilbert music reports and budget info (Box 255)
  - The functions of the Four Star Television Music Department, 1960 May 20 (Box 281)
  - Unidentified Sound Recording, 1957 May 26 - 1958 May 21; open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 155)
    Tape reels: 798-800.
  - Four Star and BNP Themes, 1963; open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 149)
    Tape Reel: 727.
- CBS, Series 12.
  - Assorted Materials, 1962-1973 (Box 255)
    Columbia Pictures Corporation Square Club card - blank Viacom 1970 U 1973 annual report & proxy, CBS reports on annual meetings, summary of music costs, 1963-64 season, CBS music cost estimates, 1963 annual report to stockholders of CBS, CBS medical insurance plan for employees 1962, letter of termination formalizing HB Gilbert's departure from CBS, staff names and contact info, monies due HBG 1964-65, HB Gilbert Personnel Record and agreement, contracts/agreements with CBS, financial and compensation records & bills, booklet "CBS Enters the 70s", reprint of Harper's article
  - CBS recording musicians list, music recording log and financial statements, 1964 (Box 268)
  - CBS staff benefits, insurance, pension, stock information (Box 255)
  - Stationary (Box 255)
    CBS Television Network Stationery - Herschel Burke Gilbert, Executive Music Director, Hollywood
  - Studio Center Telephone Directory, 1964 August (Box 255)
  - Telephone Directory, Hollywood, 1964 June (Box 255)
- Photographs, Series 13.
  - Rosemary Clooney, Andre Previn, Max Steiner (Box 248)
- Financial Papers, Series 14.
  - Bill from Harry E. Taylor, Copyists-Proofreaders-Librarians, 1957 (Box 253)
  - Budget for Company Operation (Box 261)
  - Capitol Records, 1955-1958 (Box 268)
  - Claim, 1965 (Box 250)
    by U.S. Resident to Exemption from United Kingdom Income Tax on Interest, Royalties etc.
  - Consortium Records, 1964-1980 (Box 271)
  - Invoices, 1957 (Box 253)
  - John Paul Music documents dealing with expenses, 1958-1963 (Box 252)
  - Ledger of business & automobile expenses, and income, 1946-1954 (Box 271)
  - Loan by Gilbert on behalf of Arthur Hoerl and Arthur Dreifuss, 1950 (Box 288)
    Correspondence and documents relating to loan by HB Gilbert on behalf of Arthur Hoerl and Arthur Dreifuss 1950
  - Unique Records, 1957 (Box 270)
    recording budgets
  - United Artists Corporation (Box 270)
    related to budgets
  - United Kingdom Income Tax form, 1972 (Box 252)
- Promotional Materials, Series 15.
  - Correspondence re: record promotion (Box 253)
    including Moon is Blue, The Thief, Beyond a Reasonable Doubt, The Bold & the Brave
  - Correspondence re: record promotion for Oh Daddy and How Wrong You Are (Box 253)
  - Gilbert motion picture, television and record credits, 1998 February 24 (Box 271)
    with resume
  - Jimmy Joyce Family Album order form and Family Show flyer (Box 253)
  - List of Los Angeles Disc Jockeys, one on RKO Radio Pictures letterhead (Box 252)
  - Michel Michelet, Music & Poems by Frances Libaw (Box 253)
  - Phil Bennett Lyric for There's a Big Change Coming in Seventy-Two (Box 253)
  - Publicity Advertisements, 1952-1984 (Box 289)
    Publicity: Ads, notices, articles, publicity blurbs in newspapers, The Reporter, Daily Variety 1952-1984, mostly 1953-1954 including The Ring, The Moon is Blue, Witness to Murder, The Thief, Carmen Jones, specific mentions of Herschel Gilbert
  - Record covers for 45s (Box 253)
    : Theme from Maverick, Tales of Wells Fargo, Gunsmoke, Perry Como Round and Round, The Californians, Wagon Train, Jim Bowie, Happy Trails Roy Rogers and Dale Evans, Jim Bowie, Perry Como Catch a Falling Star, Broken Arrow
  - Record Distribution and Disc Jockey Lists (Box 253)
  - Record promotion expenses (Box 253)
    - handwritten sheet
  - Rocket Roden songs (Box 253)
  - Songs submitted to record companies and singers, 1957-1972 (Box 253)
- Clippings, Series 16.
  - Assorted Clippings (Box 235)
  - Assorted Clippings (Box 236)
- Blank Forms and Stationary, Series 17.
  - BMI, 1977 (Box 267)
    Publishers Clearance form and new payment schedule
  - BNP, 1959 (Box 268)
    publishing agreement for composers
  - Copyright booklets 1952, 1956, 1961, blank application for registration to copyright, and correspondence regarding H.R. 2512bill before Congress 1967, 1952-1967 (Box 268)
  - Gilbey Music Company (Box 267)
    publisher-songwriter agreement standard form
  - Gilbey Music Company and John Paul Music Corp (Box 267)
    recording license, Commercial Phonograph Rider to Publisher-songwriter agreement, recording studio work sheet
  - John Paul Music (Box 278)
    John Paul Music recording license forms, rider, and list of printing
  - Maile Records Recording Artist Agreement (Box 272)
  - Maile records stationery, envelope and block cut for envelope (Box 272)
  - Music and/or lyrics license agreement, Standard composer-producer single picture contract (1947), BNP Records artists CBS music budget (Box 268)
  - Music Corporation of America (Box 269)
    Artists questionnaire
  - original masters including Gilbert standard form motion picture contract (Box 268)
  - Publishers clearance form and index card (Box 267)
  - Transfer Record (Stereo to Monaural) (Box 237)
- Artwork, Series 18.
  - Caricatures (Box 294)
    Framed in plastic.
  - Caricatures (Box 295)
- Periodicals, Series 19.
  - Fanfare: the Magazine for Serious Record Collectors, 1980-1991 (Box 291)
    V4N1(1980)V5N1-2,6(1982)V10N5(1987)V12N3,5(1989)13N2(1989)V15N1-2(1991)
  - Fanfare: the Magazine for Serious Record Collectors, 1992-1994 (Box 292)
    V16N1,5(1992-93)V17N3(1994)
  - Hollywood Reporter and Variety, 1959-1962 (Box 278)
    pages with Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences awards info
  - The Waikiki Beach Press, 1971 November 26-28 (Box 272)
    v. 27, no. 92 with article on "Hello Hawaii"
- Sheet Music, Series 20.
  - Big Bankroll (Box 289)
    Music by Gilbert, lyric by Dee Katcher.
  - Carmen, 1952 (Box 288)
    Metropolitan Opera Libretto English translation 1952 version
  - Exodus (Box 289)
    By Ernest Gold with red markings.
  - Exodus (Box 289)
    For cello and orchestra by Ernest Gold. Marked reduction by the composer.
  - My Rumble Seat Gal (Box 289)
    From The Runner Stumbles, music by Ernest Gold, lyrics by Jeannette Keller.
  - Not Without You (Box 279)
    handwritten in pencil
  - Unidentified work (Box 289)
    On item, "FR. HN 1 Tributaries."
- Programs, Series 21.
  - 6th Annual Tour, de Paur's Infantry Chorus (Box 288)
  - de Paur's Infantry Chorus (Box 288)
  - Metropolitan Opera, 1953 (Box 288)
    70th Anniversary Metropolitan Opera House, 1953 souvenir book
  - Porgy and Bess, 1953 (Box 288)
    presented by Blevins Davis and Robert Breen
  - The Threepenny Opera (Box 288)
    Theater de Lys, presented by Carmen Capalbo & Stanley Chase
- Moving Image Materials, Series 22.
  - First Chinese Internat'l Whitman Conference, 2000 October (Box 266)
    Robert Strassburg/Walt Whitman compositions. Peking Univ.
  - Mancini; Bill Conti, 1989; VHS (Box 266)
  - Pinocchio, 35mm film (Box 299)
  - Preservation of Film Music: McNeil Lehrer, 1990; VHS (Box 266)
  - Salute to Morton Gould, 1991; VHS (Box 266)
  - SOS Honors Placido Domingo, 2002; VHS (Box 266)
- Gilbert Personal Papers, Series 23.
  - Assorted Personal Papers (Box 288)